export const gramma = [
{      
      semester: 1,
      grade: 8,
      questions: [
          {
              id: 41,
              extra: `<p><b>Multiple choice, choose answers A, B, C, D</b></p>`,
              question: `He speaks English __________.
        `,
              options: [`fluent`,`fluently`,`fluency`,`fluenting`],
              answer: `2`,
              rewrite: ``,
              lastwrite: ``,
              explanation: `"Fluently" là trạng từ, diễn đạt cách nói (speak) của động từ
        "speaks."`,
            },
            {
              id: 41,
              extra: ``,
              question: `The weather in this city is __________ than in my hometown.
        `,
              options: [`good`,`well`,`better`,`best`],
              answer: `3`,
              rewrite: ``,
              lastwrite: ``,
              explanation: `So sánh hơn (better) sử dụng "than," và "better" là tính từ so
        sánh hơn.`,
            },
            {
              id: 41,
              extra: ``,
              question: `The __________ of the internet has changed the way we live.
        `,
              options: [`appearance`,`arrive`,`advent`,`amusement`],
              answer: `3`,
              rewrite: ``,
              lastwrite: ``,
              explanation: `"Advent" nghĩa là sự xuất hiện hay sự bắt đầu của một sự kiện
        quan trọng, phù hợp trong ngữ cảnh.`,
            },
            {
              id: 41,
              extra: ``,
              question: `My sister is __________ with her decision to study abroad.
        `,
              options: [`satisfied`,`satisfying`,`satisfaction`,`satisfactorily`],
              answer: `1`,
              rewrite: ``,
              lastwrite: ``,
              explanation: `"Satisfied" là tính từ miêu tả tâm trạng của người chịu đựng,
        không cần thêm trạng từ.`,
            },
            {
              id: 41,
              extra: ``,
              question: `The chef carefully prepared the dish __________.
        `,
              options: [`delicious`,`deliciously`,`delight`,`delightful`],
              answer: `2`,
              rewrite: ``,
              lastwrite: ``,
              explanation: `"Deliciously" là trạng từ mô tả cách chuẩn bị của động từ
        "prepared."`,
            },
            {
              id: 41,
              extra: ``,
              question: `The students were __________ for their hard work during the school
        year.
        `,
              options: [`rewarded`,`rewarding`,`rewardingly`,`rewardful`],
              answer: `1`,
              rewrite: ``,
              lastwrite: ``,
              explanation: `"Rewarded" là động từ quá khứ, phù hợp trong ngữ cảnh về việc
        trao giải thưởng.`,
            },
            {
              id: 41,
              extra: ``,
              question: `The new movie was so __________ that everyone in the audience was
        crying.
        `,
              options: [`move`,`moving`,`movement`,`moved`],
              answer: `2`,
              rewrite: ``,
              lastwrite: ``,
              explanation: `"Moving" là tính từ miêu tả cảm giác của người xem.She was __________ when she found out she got the job.`,
            },
            {
              id: 41,
              extra: ``,
              question: `She was __________ when she found out she got the job.
        `,
              options: [`excited`,`excite`,`exciting`,`excitement`],
              answer: `1`,
              rewrite: ``,
              lastwrite: ``,
              explanation: `"Excited" là tính từ miêu tả tâm trạng của người chịu đựng, không
        cần thêm trạng từ.`,
            },
            {
              id: 41,
              extra: ``,
              question: `The company __________ its employees to participate in charity
        events.
        `,
              options: [`encourages`,`encouraged`,`encouraging`,`encouragement`],
              answer: `1`,
              rewrite: ``,
              lastwrite: ``,
              explanation: `"Encourages" là động từ chỉ hành động của công ty hiện tại.`,
            },
            {
              id: 41,
              extra: ``,
              question: `The old house has a lot of __________ charm.
        `,
              options: [`historic `,`historical `,`history `,`historically `],
              answer: `1`,
              rewrite: ``,
              lastwrite: ``,
              explanation: `"Historic" là tính từ miêu tả đặc điểm của ngôi nhà, không cần
        thêm trạng từ.`,
            },
      ]
  },
   {      
      semester: 1,
      grade: 8,
      questions: [
          {
              id: 41,
              extra: `<p><b>Supply the correct form of the word given in each sentence.</b></p>`,
              question: ` She sings ___________ than anyone else in the choir. (beautiful)
        `,
              options: [],
              answer: `more beautifully`,
              rewrite: ``,
              lastwrite: ``,
              explanation: ` - Sử dụng "more" để so sánh hơn với tính từ dài
        "beautiful."`,
            },
            {
              id: 41,
              extra: ``,
              question: `The professor clarified the terms ___________ to make it more
        comprehensible for the students to understand. (clear)
        `,
             options: [],
              answer: `clearly`,
              rewrite: ``,
              lastwrite: ``,
              explanation: ` - Chúng ta sử dụng trạng từ "clearly" để mô tả cách giáo viên
        giải thích.`,
            },
            {
              id: 41,
              extra: ``,
              question: `The ___________ changes in the weather affect the crops every year.
        (season)
        `,
             options: [],
              answer: `seasonal`,
              rewrite: ``,
              lastwrite: ``,
              explanation: ` - Chúng ta sử dụng tính từ "seasonal" để mô tả những thay
        đổi liên quan đến mùa.`,
            },
            {
              id: 41,
              extra: ``,
              question: `My grandparents walk ___________ in the garden every morning. (slow)
        `,
             options: [],
              answer: `slowly`,
              rewrite: ``,
              lastwrite: ``,
              explanation: ` - Sử dụng trạng từ "slowly" để mô tả cách ông nội đi bộ.`,
            },
            {
              id: 41,
              extra: ``,
              question: `The chef prepared the dish ___________ for the food critic. (perfect)
        `,
             options: [],
              answer: `perfectly`,
              rewrite: ``,
              lastwrite: ``,
              explanation: ` - Sử dụng trạng từ "perfectly" để mô tả cách đầu bếp chuẩn
        bị món ăn.`,
            },
            {
              id: 41,
              extra: ``,
              question: `He speaks English ___________ because he lived in London for a year.
        (fluent)
        `,
             options: [],
              answer: `fluently`,
              rewrite: ``,
              lastwrite: ``,
              explanation: ` - Sử dụng trạng từ "fluently" để mô tả cách anh ấy nói tiếng
        Anh.`,
            },
            {
              id: 41,
              extra: ``,
              question: `The company is known for its ___________ efforts to reduce
        environmental impact. (sustain)
        `,
             options: [],
              answer: `sustained`,
              rewrite: ``,
              lastwrite: ``,
              explanation: ` - Sử dụng tính từ "sustained" để mô tả những nỗ lực kéo dài
        của công ty.`,
            },
            {
              id: 41,
              extra: ``,
              question: `The test-takers answered the questions ___________ in the
        examination. (correct)
        `,
             options: [],
              answer: `correctly`,
              rewrite: ``,
              lastwrite: ``,
              explanation: ` - Sử dụng trạng từ "correctly" để mô tả cách học sinh trả
        lời câu hỏi.`,
            },
            {
              id: 41,
              extra: ``,
              question: `The athletes finished the competition ___________ than expected.
        (quick)
        `,
             options: [],
              answer: `more quickly`,
              rewrite: ``,
              lastwrite: ``,
              explanation: ` - Sử dụng "more" để so sánh hơn với tính từ dài "quick."`,
            },
            {
              id: 41,
              extra: ``,
              question: `The ___________ design of the new museum is quite inspiring.
        (architect)
        `,
             options: [],
              answer: `architectural`,
              rewrite: ``,
              lastwrite: ``,
              explanation: ` - Sử dụng tính từ "architectural" để mô tả đặc điểm
        của kiến trúc.`,
            },
      ]
  },
]
